latpro.com 2019-07-02

# Privacy Statement | LatPro.com

### **This document is the official PRIVACY POLICY for LATPRO, INC., which does business as LatPro.com, DiversityJobs.com, JustJobs.com and other affiliated websites, including:**

africanamericanhires.com, allairportjobs.com, allanalystjobs.com, allautomotivejobs.com, allbilingualjobs.com, allconstructionjobs.com, allcounselingjobs.com, alldialysisjobs.com, alleducationjobs.com, allfoodjobs.com, allhispanicjobs.com, alljobsinnursing.com, alllanguagejobs.com, alllgbtjobs.com, alloutdoorjobs.com, allschooljobs.com, allspanishjobs.com, architecturejobs.org, asianhires.com, butlerjobs.org, cablejobs.org, civilengineeringjobs.org, collegefacultyjobs.com, commercialconstructionjobs.org, computerjobs.net, disabilityjobs.net, driverjobs.org, engineeringjobs.org, ethanoljobs.org, facilitiesjobs.org, fieldjobs.org, fortwaynejobs.org, geriatricjobs.org, horticulturejobs.org, insurancejobs.org, jobsinaccounting.org, jobsinbanking.com, jobsinfinance.org, jobsinhealthcare.com, jobsinhospitality.net, jobsinhospitals.org, jobsinhr.org, jobsinit.org, jobsinlasvegas.org, jobsinnonprofit.org, jobsinoperations.com, jobsinscience.org, jobsinsoftware.org, jobsinteaching.org, jobsintucson.org, justparttimejobs.com, latinojobs.org, logisticsjobs.org, marketingjobs.org, mortgageconsultantjobs.org, neonatologyjobs.org, nursingwork.org, payrolljobs.org, professorjobs.org, qajobs.com, retailjobs.org, rockcountyjobs.org, salesjobs.org, sustainabilityjobs.org, transportationjobs.org, truckjobs.org, veteranjobs.net, wehirewomen.com, latproinc.com, diversityjobsalerts.com, latpromail.com, justjobs.us

This Privacy Policy explains how, when and why your personal data is being processed by LatPro, Inc., which does business as DiversityJobs.com, LatPro.com as well as all the websites listed in the above paragraph.

For the purpose of this policy, any reference to **“LatPro, Inc.” , “us”, “we” or “our”** shall mean any applicable company or website with LatPro, Inc. as the parent company.

LatPro, Inc. is the data controller of any personal data and other information you provide when using our any of aforementioned websites. LatPro, Inc. always processes Personal Data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) as well as any national legislation, regulations applicable to the processing of personal data.

Your rights to privacy and integrity are important to us and we are therefore cautious with handling your personal data and thrive to limit the processing only to information that is required in order to perform our services to you.

 **Security**

LatPro, Inc. has implemented and follows industry standard measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception or processing of Personal Data. However, no internet site can fully eliminate all security risks.

 **Your Consent**

By using these websites you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

###  **Personal Data**

Personal data is any kind of information that directly or indirectly refers to an identified or identifiable person or data that could possibly would allow a party to contact you, including, for example, your full name, address, telephone number, or email address.

All personal information is used solely to provide you with the services you’ve requested.

###  **Data Removal Requests**

For any account removal request, please send an email [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

##  **Services we provide and data we need to process in order to render these services**

###  **Services for Jobseekers**

As a Job Board or Employment Website, we are a medium where Job seekers may apply for jobs posted on our websites and where they can be found and contacted by our employer clients.  Both these jobseeker services are free.

 **Searching and Applying for jobs –** In order to apply to jobs you may be required to register your profile and upload a resume. In many cases this is optional but, in such cases, you will likely be required to supply personal data directly on our clients’ websites or Applicant Tracking Systems.

The jobs found on LatPro, Inc. have been created by third parties over which LatPro, Inc. exercises no control. LatPro, Inc. assumes no responsibility for the content of any job posting found on LatPro, Inc.’s websites.

 **Resume Database –** If you’d like to “be found” by employers and recruiters in our jobseeker database, you are required to register and/or upload a resume.

When you register your jobseeker account on our websites, it is assumed that you are looking for employment opportunities with our client companies and that you are comfortable being contacted by them.  If you uploaded your resume, your full resume text and contact information is available for our recruiter clients searching our resume database. Our recruiters are prohibited to use your information for any other use other than for hiring purposes.

Any requested demographic information, such as gender and race is optional. If you provide that information, rest assured it is strictly used for marketing or research purposes. Demographics may be shared with clients as aggregate statistics but will NEVER directly linked to an individual!

Jobseeker accounts are deleted after 5 years of inactivity.

You may also contact webmaster@latpro-inc.com to solicit removal request or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

###  **Services for Recruiters**

Our Recruiter clients may purchase single job posting ads, hire us to scrape unlimited jobs, buy access to our candidate resume database and buy booth space at our Job Fairs.

In order to take advantage of these services, recruiters are required to register the company they represent. They are required to enter your personal data, as well as information pertaining to your business, including your name, job title, company name, work address, work email address, work telephone, billing contact, etc.

 **Use of payment service providers**

When you pay for our services, you need to enter your credit card or an address where we can send you an invoice.

For Credit card processing, we use Bank of America and Authorize.net to provide credit card processing on our site.  When you submit payment information, we securely transmit Personally Identifiable Information and Credit Card number, as necessary, for the third party to provide that service.

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

##  **Other services which use your email and/or your personal data**

 **Job Agents**

Job Agents is a free service that allows you to receive job announcements via email.  In order to create a Job Agent, we must collect your email and the search criteria for each agent. This email address is never shared or sold to third parties.  All emails that we send include a unsubscription link at the bottom of the content.

You may also contact [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) to solicit removal request or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

 **Targeted emails**

Similar to a Job Agent, we send emails on behalf of our companies, regarding a job opportunities that fit your profile and geographical location using emails from our Resume database.  All emails that we send include a unsubscription link at the bottom of the content. You may also contact [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) to solicit removal request or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

 **Newsletters**

We have 2 monthly newsletters, Hispanic Recruiter Review and Latin Career News. When you subscribe to our Newsletters, it is necessary for us to collect your e-mail address. While we may place an advertisement on the newsletters.  All emails that we send include a unsubscription link at the bottom of the content.

Emails collected on our newsletters remain there until you delete them or ask us to do so.

You may also contact [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) to solicit removal request or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

 **Administrative emails**

If we have your email or resume on our database, you may receive administrative emails pertaining to your account, such as expiration notices, password retrieval, etc.

While you have any type of account on our websites, there is no way to prevent us from sending Administrative emails unless you choose to discontinue our services, which you can do by contacting [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) or via other contact methods featured at the bottom of this document.

 **Career Fair invitations**

If your email or resume is on our database, we may send you an invitation to a job fair happening in your area.  All such emails that we send include a unsubscription link at the bottom of the content. You may also contact [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com) to solicit removal request or use the contact information at the bottom of this document.

 **Blog Comments**

Some of our websites have blogs or pages that allow users to make a comment. In order to leave a comment your are required to leave your name and email. The name is visible to the public but the email is not.  That email is not shared and it’s solely used by us, in case we need to reach you.

 **Contact forms**

In order to provide customer or sales support, we use contact forms in various parts of our websites. When you contact us using these forms, we do ask for your contact information so that we can promptly respond.  Those contact logs are purged after 45 days.

 **Sharing Data with third parties**

When you add your resume to our database, we may ask you for consent to share your resume with 3rd party services offering career related services, such as Resume editing, assessment tests, etc.  

 **Your personal data is** **NEVER** **shared to a 3rd party** **without your consent** **.**

 **Diversity Job Fairs**

Aside from our job boards, we produce (physical/non-virtual) Career Fairs in various US Metro areas. During those job fairs, we collect resumes.  Those paper resumes are then scanned and made available to attending recruiters. Our recruiters are prohibited to use your information for any other use other than for hiring purposes.  

Prior to the job fair, candidates are encouraged to RSVP to the events via a third party website, EventBrite.com.  For more information on EventBrite’s privacy compliance, please visit: [https://www.eventbrite.com/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-eu-data-protection ](https://www.eventbrite.com/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-eu-data-protection)

**Surveys**

We occasionally post Surveys using a 3rd party service called SurveyMonkey. For more information on Survey Monkey’s GDPR compliance, visit: <https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/gdpr/>

Surveys are never mandatory and never a requirement for job application.

 **Google Analytics**

We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information from Google Analytics only to improve this site and our user experience. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use (<https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>) and the Google Privacy Policy(<https://policies.google.com/privacy>). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser: <https://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions>

## **Cookies**

We use cookies. A cookie is a small data file that our website plants on your hard drive. Our cookie files contain information such as a user ID and statistic data to complete and handle our association-related activities and surveys. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you have supplied yourself. Our cookies cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Cookies are used to track user traffic patterns. We do this in order to evaluate our user’s patterns and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users to acquire association-related information, participate in association-related activities and complete surveys as effectively as possible. If you are logged in on your Facebook- or Google+ account while accessing LatPro, Inc. websites, data may be transferred through cookies about your usage. This may result in Facebook and/or Google collecting personal data about you, whereby their respective terms and policies apply (accessed here: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation> and <https://www.google.se/intl/en_se/policies/privacy/?fg=1>).

Through the settings of your web browser, you can manage how and when processing of cookies should be possible. However, please note that disabling us from processing cookies may affect the usage of our Sites and some functions may not work properly.

 **More information about cookies:** <https://www.latpro.com/c/cookies-in-use-on-this-site/>

## **Your rights to obtain extract, correction, erasure etc.**

You have the right to obtain an extract of the information LatPro, Inc. websites holds about you. If you want to obtain such a statement, or if you wish to correct information or data, object to, or restrict a certain processing of your data, you are welcome to contact LatPro, Inc. websites at [webmaster@latpro-inc.com](mailto:webmaster@latpro-inc.com). LatPro, Inc. will also assist you, if requested at the aforementioned e-mail address, with the transmitting of your data to another controller (so-called “data portability”), and/or delete information regarding you and/or your use of the Site. However, please be aware that if you ask us to delete all information from your user account you will no longer be able to use the parts of the Sites where a user account is mandatory for access.

We hope that questions regarding our processing of your personal data can be resolved effectively through communication between us. However, please be informed that you always have the right to file an objection with the Federal Trade Commission, regarding our processing of your Personal Data.

 **Updates**

This privacy policy may be updated without prior notice. In case of any significant changes or updates, LatPro, Inc. will send you an email and/or post a notification on our webpages.

 **Contact Details**

We hope this policy clarifies our treatment of your Personal Data.  Please do not hesitate to contact us by mail, e-mail or phone with questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or any other issue related to our websites or business.

LatPro, Inc.  
3980 North Broadway, ste 103-147  
Boulder, CO 80304  
Tel: 954-727-3844  
Fax: 954-727-3845  
webmaster@latpro-inc.com
